

+92.307.5164728



khattakahmed1994@gmail.com



Bhara Kahu, Islamabad, Pakistan

Summary

I am a self starter, quick learner and highly resourceful, able to work independently on tasks with minimal supervision, able to make pragmatic decisions where they matter and research new ways to improve efficiency and productivity in all facets of work.

Skills

CSS3 | HTML | JavaScript | MySQL | NodeJs | React JS | TypeScript

Experience

Jun 2018 - Jan 2019

IOS Developer

KonstantVariable, Islamabad, Pakistan

- Translating designs and business requirements to code.
- Initiated work on a design system to reduce prototype design time.
- Researching new ways to improve product codebase and developer velocity.
- Using git version control to manage multiple features.
- Adding unit tests to increase stability and reliability of codebase.

May 2018 - Sep 2018

Freelancer at Upwork

Upwork, Islamabad, Pakistan

Joined Upwork as a freelancer where I

- Developed chrome extensions for international clients.
- Dropshipping ecommerce widget
- Created a video modifier extension for videojs

Jun 2016 - Sep 2016

Android Developer Intern

Buisness Incubation Center Bahria, Islamabad, Pakistan

Completed degree requirement of an internship

- Learned Startup culuture
- Learned Teamwork
- Learned Android Development

Jan 2015 - Mar 2015

Community Service Volunteer

Humanetek, Islamabad, Pakistan

- Assisted community members and colleagues
- Learned teamwork and planning
- Spend quality time with underpriveliged children

Education

2020		Bahria University MSc DATA SCIENCE CGPA: 3.5/4
2017	0	Bahria University BSc Computer Science CGPA: 3.1/4
2013		Bahria College Intermediate/A-Level Computer Science
2010	0	Bahria College Matriculation/O-Level Computer Science

Projects

COVID-19 Dashboard in React

https://covid-19-dashboard-react.now.sh/

This is a simple project i made to learn **React**. This Dashboard is built using React. The API for the dashboard is provided by https://about-corona.net/documentation.

Features

- View global graphs of recovery, cases, and death rate.
- View recovery rate and fatality rate
- View detailed information on map
- View Table of all countries and relevant covid-19 stats
- View local graphs of recovery, cases, and death rate.
- View WHO twitter feed.

Technical stuff for interviewers

This project makes use of the following:

- Typescript
- React Hooks
- React HOC
- React Router
- MapBox
- Integrating a non react library into react
- Recharts and Nivo Charts integration
- Performance optimization using React.PureComponent
- Fetching and transforming external data
- Local Caching to improve performance on page navigation
- Front End monitoring using sentry

Bahria University Student Portal Chrome Extension

Developed a Chrome Browser Extension that saved the entire Student Portal Website of Bahria University due to its frequent down time.

- Used local storage to make offline cache work
- Stored the entire portal site by scanning through its site map

• One click operation to load the locally stored site

Bahria University Student Portal App

Developed an android app for bahria university islamabad in collboration with IT department which was in use at all campuses. The app provided a more streamlined access to the university portal.

- Provided ReCaptcha Completion
- Used local device caching for enabling offline access
- Had a better UX/UI than the university student portal
- Was in use at its peak by 3000 students around all campuses in karachi, islamabad, and lahore.
- Technology used was android, git, and java.

Languages

Pashto

Expert